# Hyung-Kwon Ko

College of Computing KAIST, Daejeon hyungkwonko@gmail.com https://hyungkwonko.info

#### About

Hyung-Kwon Ko is a researcher at KAIST Interaction Lab, focusing on Human-Computer Interaction, Human-Centered AI, and Information Visualization. He develops intelligent systems to solve complex problems of communication between humans or when interacting with computers by adopting sophisticated algorithms or novel interaction techniques. Experienced in AI models from both academia and industry, he is interested in innovating our society with technology and becoming an irreplaceable person who can make the future happen.

#### Education

2019 – 2021	<b>Seoul National University</b> , Seoul, Korea Master of Science in Computer Science and Engineering (Advisor: Dr. Jinwook Seo)
2014 – 2019	Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea Bachelor of Science in Mathematics, Minor in Industrial Engineering

#### **Publications**

Conference & Journal Papers

- [a7] Jeon, H., Cho, A., Jang, J., Lee, S., Hyun, J., Ko, H.-K., Jo, J., Seo, J. (2023).
  Zadu: A python library for evaluating the reliability of dimensionalit reduction embeddings.
  IEEE Visualization Conference (VIS '23), to appear.
- [a6] Ko, H.-K., Park, G., Jeon, H., Jo, J., Kim, J., Seo, J. (2023).
  Large-scale Text-to-Image Generation Models for Visual Artists' Creative Works.
  International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces (IUI '23), 1-15.
- [a5] Ko, H.-K.\*, An, S.\*, Park, G., Kim, S.K., Kim, D., Kim, B., Jo, J., Seo, J. (2022).
  We-toon: A Communication Support System between Writers and Artists in Collaborative Webtoon Sketch Revision.
  ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (UIST '22), 1-14.
- [a4] Jeon, H.\*, Ko, H.-K.\*, Lee, S., Jo, J., Seo, J. (2022).

  Uniform Manifold Approximation with Two-phase Optimization.

  IEEE Visualization Conference (VIS '22), 80-84.
- [a3] Jeon, H., Ko, H.-K., Jo, J., Kim, Y., Seo, J. (2021).
   Measuring and Explaining the Inter-Cluster Reliability of Multidimensional Projections.
   IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (In Proceedings of VIS '21), 28(1):551-561.
- [a2] Jung, S., Choe, K., Park, S., <u>Ko, H.-K.</u>, Seo, J. (2021).

  Mixed-Initiative Approach to Extract Data from Pictures of Medical Invoice.

  IEEE Pacific Visualization Symposium (PacificVis '21), 111-115.
- [a1] Ko, H.-K., Jo, J., Seo, J. (2020).

  Progressive Uniform Manifold Approximation and Projection.

  EG/VGTC Conference on Visualization (EuroVis '20), 133-137.

Workshop Papers

[b2] Ko, H.-K., Jeon, H., Park, G., Kim, D. H., Kim, N. W., Kim, J., Seo, J. (2023).
 A Vega-Lite Dataset and Natural Language Generation Pipeline with Large Language Models.
 VIS 2023 NLVIZ Workshop: Exploring Research Opportunities for NL, Text, and Data Visualization

[b1] Ko, H.-K., Son, K., Jin, H., Choi, Y., Chen, X. (2023).

Moderating Customer Inquiries and Responses to Alleviate Stress and Reduce Emotional Dissonance of Customer Service Representatives.

CHI 2023 Workshop on Generative AI and HCI

#### Preprints & Publications in Progress

[c2] Shin, H., Lee, Y., Ko, H.-K., Kim, J. (2023).

Enabling Prototyping of AI-infused UIs with Task-level Specifications.

(In Progress)

[c1] Jeon, H., Aupetit, M., Lee, S., Ko, H.-K., Kim, Y., Seo, J. (2022).
 Distortion-Aware Brushing for Interactive Cluster Analysis in Multidimensional Projections.
 Arxiv Preprint (Under Review)

## **Experience**

06/2022 – Present	KAIST Interaction Lab (KIXLAB), Daejeon, Korea Researcher (Advisor: Dr. Juho Kim)
10/2021 – 06/2022	Naver Webtoon Corp., Seongnam, Korea AI Research Scientist, Webtoon AI
04/2021 - 09/2021	Naver Webtoon Corp., Seongnam, Korea AI Research Intern, Webtoon AI
03/2019 – 08/2019	Human-Computer Interaction Lab, Seoul, Korea Research Intern (Advisor: Dr. Jinwook Seo)
01/2019 - 02/2019	LG Electronics Inc., Seoul, Korea Research Intern, CTO Division
06/2018 – 08/2018	Wesleyquest Inc., Seoul, Korea Research Associate

## Honors and Awards

2023	ACM Travel Grants (Travel support for IUI '23: \$980 USD), ACM SIGCHI
2022	Gary Marsden Travel Awards (Travel support for UIST '22: \$2,800 USD), ACM SIGCHI
2018	Big Data Contest (3rd Place, Prize Money: \$900 USD), NIA and Korea Big Data Forum
2018	AI Novel Writing Competition (2 <sup>nd</sup> Place, Prize Money: \$18,000 USD), KT Corporation and KOCCA
2017	Academic Research Competition (2 <sup>nd</sup> Place, Prize Money: \$180 USD), Hanyang University
2014 - 2018	Merit-based Scholarship (6 semesters), Hanyang University

### **Invited Talks and Seminars**

<sup>\*</sup> denotes equal contributions.

1. Large-scale Text-to-Image Generation Models for Visual Artists' Creative Works Shandong University, Qingdao, China. January 2023.

## **Academic Services**

Paper ACM CHI ('23), CHI LBW ('23), C&C ('23)

Reviewing IEEE PacificVis ('20, '21)

STUDENT ACM UIST ('22), IUI ('23)

Volunteering

## **Press Coverage**

Nov 2022 <u>The Road to Becoming a Published Researcher</u>, *IEEE Computer Society*Aug 2018 <u>Writing Novels on Its Own... AI Contests Human Creativity</u>, *KBS (Korean)* 

3 / 3

Last updated: Aug 5, 2023